<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<home>

    <paragraph
        content="An important collaboration was undertaken between the machinery manufacturing and machine tools industries, the most crucial sectors for the realization of Turkey’s 2023 vision, which requires that the volume of exports rises to 500 billion dollars and per capita income is increased to 25 thousand dollars so that Turkey can become one of the 10 largest economies of the world. As a result of their first-time cooperation, the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB) are jointly organizing the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, the largest gathering platform for the machinery industry in Eurasia. The fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center.\n\nHaving the power to directly influence industrialization and the competitive power of many sectors through technological development, the national professional organizations of manufacturers of machine tools, which are the main production tool of the machinery and manufacturing industries, entered into an important collaboration for the first time in their history and took a crucial step towards Turkey's vision for 2023. The Ministry of Science, Industry and Technology of Turkey also supports the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, organized jointly by the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB), representatives of two strategic sectors that complement each other and have set an ambitious exports goal of 100 billion dollars for Turkey’s 500 billion-dollar 2023 vision. Organized for the second time this year, the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center in Büyükçekmece. The fair will be a significant stage in the development of the coordination and innovative collaborations between these strategic sectors."
        title="A great step was taken towards the country’s 2023 vision" />

    <paragraph
        content="An important collaboration was undertaken between the machinery manufacturing and machine tools industries, the most crucial sectors for the realization of Turkey’s 2023 vision, which requires that the volume of exports rises to 500 billion dollars and per capita income is increased to 25 thousand dollars so that Turkey can become one of the 10 largest economies of the world. As a result of their first-time cooperation, the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB) are jointly organizing the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, the largest gathering platform for the machinery industry in Eurasia. The fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center.\n\nHaving the power to directly influence industrialization and the competitive power of many sectors through technological development, the national professional organizations of manufacturers of machine tools, which are the main production tool of the machinery and manufacturing industries, entered into an important collaboration for the first time in their history and took a crucial step towards Turkey's vision for 2023. The Ministry of Science, Industry and Technology of Turkey also supports the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, organized jointly by the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB), representatives of two strategic sectors that complement each other and have set an ambitious exports goal of 100 billion dollars for Turkey’s 500 billion-dollar 2023 vision. Organized for the second time this year, the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center in Büyükçekmece. The fair will be a significant stage in the development of the coordination and innovative collaborations between these strategic sectors."
        title="A great step was taken towards the country’s 2023 vision" />

</home>