<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<offices>
    <paragraph
        content="An important collaboration was undertaken between the machinery manufacturing and machine tools industries, the most crucial sectors for the realization of Turkey’s 2023 vision, which requires that the volume of exports rises to 500 billion dollars and per capita income is increased to 25 thousand dollars so that Turkey can become one of the 10 largest economies of the world. As a result of their first-time cooperation, the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB) are jointly organizing the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, the largest gathering platform for the machinery industry in Eurasia. The fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center.\n\nHaving the power to directly influence industrialization and the competitive power of many sectors through technological development, the national professional organizations of manufacturers of machine tools, which are the main production tool of the machinery and manufacturing industries, entered into an important collaboration for the first time in their history and took a crucial step towards Turkey's vision for 2023. The Ministry of Science, Industry and Technology of Turkey also supports the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair, organized jointly by the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD) and Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB), representatives of two strategic sectors that complement each other and have set an ambitious exports goal of 100 billion dollars for Turkey’s 500 billion-dollar 2023 vision. Organized for the second time this year, the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair will take place on October 14-19 at the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center in Büyükçekmece. The fair will be a significant stage in the development of the coordination and innovative collaborations between these strategic sectors."
        title="Strategic sectors united their powers\nA great step was taken towards the country’s 2023 vision"/>

    <paragraph
        content="More than 80% of machine tools production in Turkey is realized by TIAD members. Working for the interests of the country and its members, TIAD became a member of the European Trade Association for Machine Tools, Tooling and Technologies (CELIMO) in 2000. CELIMO represents 1,200 machine tools distributors whose total capital exceeds 10 billion Euros and makes up an essential market for Turkish exporters. Together with the TIAD Academy and TIAD Professional Test Center under the Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen’s Association (TIAD), the growth of industry professionals is supported.\n\nChairman of MAKTEK Eurasia, İlhan Ersözlü commented that 13 billion dollars in exports were realized in 2013 by the machinery industry, which plans to be the largest export sector with a share of 100 billion dollars in Turkey's 2023 target of 500 billion-dollar exports, and said: “The Turkish machinery industry gained significant momentum in a short period of 10 years and has maintained this success in 2012 and 2013. The rate of exports to imports in the Turkish machinery industry increased from 27% to 43% in the last ten years. In 2012 and 2013, the industry made exports to 200 countries, primarily industrialized countries including Germany, UK, USA, France, Iraq, Russia and Italy. In machinery exports, Turkey rose to 27th place in 2012 from 35th place in 2001 globally, and from 18th place in 2001 to 15th place in 2012 in Europe. According to the data of the Turkish Statistical Institute (TUIK), the employment volume of the machinery sector reached 154 thousand people in 2010."
        title="Exports to developed countries"/>

    <paragraph
        content="The current 165 members of the Association of Machinery Manufacturers (MIB) realize 60-65% of investment type machinery exports. Companies that are well known in their own sector export investment machinery to more than 100 countries. Europe is the most important component of foreign trade, followed by the Middle East, Asian countries, the Far East and America. The members represented by MIB increased their exports by 6.14% in 2013, reaching a volume of 493.6 million dollars. According to Gardner's Machine Tools Report dated 27 February 2014, the Turkish Machine Tools sector increased its exports volume from 429.50 million dollars in 2012 to 471.40 million dollars in 2013. Turkey’s global ranking in machine tools exports rose from 16th place to 15th place."
        title="Turkey’s position in the sector is improving globally"/>

    <paragraph
        content="The most important manufacturers of machine tools, the basic production tool of the machinery industry and manufacturing industry, will come together at the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair. More than 1,000 companies and company representatives from Turkey and all around the world will participate in the MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair. The fair has become one of the most preferred exhibitions of the world with national groups from Germany, France, Spain, China, UK and Taiwan. Due to increased participation, 14 halls of the TÜYAP Fair and Congress Center, which has an indoor capacity of 120,000 square meters, will be utilized at full capacity. Companies operating in machine tools, milling machines, retainers, cutting tools, quality control-measurement systems, CAD/CAM, PLM software programs and manufacturing technologies will be exhibiting at the fair."
        title="MAKTEK Eurasia 2014 Fair"/>

    <paragraph
        content="TÜYAP Tüm Fuarcılık Yapım A.Ş.\n\nBurak GÜRSES\nProject Marketing Officer\nDirect line: +90 212 867 12 96\nburakgurses@tuyap.com.tr\n\nEce ÇAĞLAR\nProject Marketing Representative\nDirect line: +90 212 867 12 25\nececaglar@tuyap.com.tr\n\nDuygu Duman / Ogilvy PR\n(0212) 339 83 83\nduygu.duman@ogilvy.com"
        title="For more information:"/>
</offices>