<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<home>

    <paragraph
        content="Machine Tools Industrialists and Businessmen Association (TIAD) of Turkey is a professional organization established in 1992 with the aim of gathering industrialists and businessmen dealing with imports, exports, manufacturing, wholesale and/or retail trade of machine tools, their complementary accessories and tooling equipment; which are among the fundamental means of the manufacturing processes. The mission of the Association is to represent its members in the best way on all national and international platforms.\n\nBy 2012, the year of the 20th Establishment Anniversary, the number of TIAD members has reached 158 and more than 80 % of the machine tools demand in Turkey is met by TIAD members.\n\nTIAD performs activities both for the benefit of the country and its members. These activities are carried out through Committees and Working Groups constituted within its corporate structure. In this framework, TIAD has Fair Organizations, Laws and Regulations, Foreign Relations and EU Projects, Membership Development and Coordination, After Sales Services, Media and Advertising, Training, Science and Technology Committees, as well as “Working Groups” of Tooling, Metrology and CAD / CAM.\n\nTIAD became a member of the European Trade Association for Machine Tools, Tooling and Technologies (CELIMO) as of 2000.  Having presided over CELIMO in the 2006-2008 term, TIAD still holds Board Member status in this international association. CELIMO currently represents 1,200 machine tool distributor companies holding more than 10 billion Euro total capital, and it constitutes a fundamental market for Turkey’s exporters."
        title="MACHINE TOOLS INDUSTRIALISTS AND BUSINESSMEN ASSOCIATION"/>

    <paragraph
        content="TIAD represents its members at public bodies, chambers and equivalent associations, universities and other similar institutions; TIAD participates in many national and international meetings in order to support development of solutions for sectorial matters, while submitting its opinions to contribute to all sectorial efforts carried out on these platforms.\n\nWithin this scope, TIAD is a natural member of “Technical Committee on Machinery (MAKTEK) which was established by Communiqué No. SGM 2003/8 on the Formation and Duties of the Mechanical Technical Committee published in the Turkish Official Gazette No. 25245, dated 09.30.2003 and later replaced by Communiqué No. SGM 2009/10 published in the Turkish Official Gazette No. 27264, dated 24.06.2009.\n\nMAKTEK is one of the four-teen official sectorial technical committees established by the Turkish Ministry of Science, Industry and Technology and in line with Turkey’s commitment for European Union (EU) membership, to act as platforms where private sector representatives discuss the problems with public authorities arising from their practical sectorial issues. MAKTEK convenes according to a regular schedule, present proposals to the Ministry as well as to other relevant institutions and may form sub-working groups in order to assess and strengthen the competitiveness of the sectors.\n\nIn this context, there is a Machine Tools Sub-Working Group formed by MAKTEK Decision dated June 8, 2004 and operating under MAKTEK, the Chairmanship of which is currently being carried out by TIAD.\n\nTIAD has participated in the preparation processes of the “Turkish Industrial Strategy and Action Plan (2011 – 2014)” and the “Turkish Machinery Sector Strategy and Action Plan (2011 – 2014)”, which constitute significant road maps and played an active role in the mentioned processes. TIAD is among the members of the “Steering Board” formed in order to apply, follow and assess “Turkey’s Machinery Sector Strategy and Action Plan”.\n\nThe membership of the “Union of Chambers and Commodity Exchanges of Turkey (TOBB)”, Machinery and Equipment Manufacturing Sector Assembly is among the other major representation activities of TIAD."
        title="Representation Activities and Events"/>

    <paragraph
        content="TIAD organizes sectorial and general informing activities for its members on its own or in cooperation with governmental institutions, chambers and equivalent associations, universities, occupational and technical training and other similar institutions. These activities are organized as workshops, conferences, congresses, seminars and panel discussions.\n\nIn addition to applied occupational technical training for professionals and students, TIAD also provides personal development trainings regarding imports and exports, sales and marketing, customer relations, legal, financial and administrative issues."
        title="Sectorial Cooperation and Informing Activities"/>

    <paragraph
        content="A “Cooperation Protocol” was signed between TIAD and Bahçeşehir University Vocational School of Higher Education (METGEM) in order to develop cooperation for theoretical and applied training on 18th February 2010. Within the scope of the protocol, training opportunities for Vocational High School students are provided every year.\n\nOn 7th June 2012, a “Cooperation Protocol” between TIAD and Haydarpaşa Technical and Industrial Vocational High School was signed in order to meet the requirement for qualified manpower in the industrial cast branch of machinery technology field. Due to this cooperation, the necessary operations are being carried out to meet the need for qualified high school graduate personnel, with consideration to requirements of the sector.\n\nTIAD also performs supportive activities as an Advisory Board member at Small and Medium Enterprises (SME’s) and Productivity Congresses organized by Kültür University."
        title="Cooperation between Industrial and Educational Institutions"/>

    <paragraph
        content="In order to contribute to the provision of qualified manpower required for our country and to support the need for qualified technical personnel required by the whole manufacturing sector, especially by TIAD members, TIAD provides occupational and technical training under the roof of TIAD Academy with experience and assurance guaranteed.\n\nTIAD Academy, which provides services for the use of CNC systems in Turkish industry, conceptualizes projects, directs and supports the manufacturing processes, provides more efficient operation of machine tools used in manufacturing sectors by training qualified personnel, increases the production capacity of companies and  reduces the work process costs of machinery, is a training center possessing all the technical equipment and competence required for these services.\n\nTIAD Academy contributes to the progress and development of Turkey by providing the correct, efficient and effective use of “Machine Tools”, described as “the main tools to produce manufacturing machinery” which are essential in various manufacturing industries, especially in automotive, white goods, defence, machinery, aeronautics, ship construction, textiles, cast, construction, aircraft, food and furniture sectors. Within TIAD Academy, training programmes are developed and applied to realize the target of producing intermediate goods used in most manufacturing sectors with less cost and producing more value added products and exporting them to the whole world.\n\nTIAD Academy provides three kinds of training, one of which is Group Training in its own building, and others being on-site Group Training and Private Training.\n\nThe training includes topics for the Programming of CNC Machine Tools, Computer Aided Design (CAD), Computer Aided Manufacturing (CAM), Technical Drawing and Tolerancing. All training is completed in 40 hours in principle, and especially the applied part of the Programming of CNC Workstations training is very important and therefore time planning of this training is scheduled as 20 % theoretical and 80 % applied training. TIAD Academy’s competent instructors staff consist of people with both an academic educational background and industrial sector experience. Interactive training, where the plant environment is precisely simulated, provides the opportunity for experiencing the probable situations and problems which the participants may be subjected to."
        title="TIAD Academy – Applied Occupational and Technical Training"/>

    <paragraph
        content="Science and Technology of Machining, CNC Machine Tools and Automation of Manufacturing, by Prof. Dr. MustafaAkkurt\n\nCommunity Legislation on Machinery\n\nMachining Science and Technology, CNC Machine Tools and Manufacturing Automation, by Prof. Dr. Mustafa Akkurt"
        title="Technical Publications"/>

    <paragraph
        content="In March 2011, TIAD was awarded a grant by the European Union (EU),with the approval of and through the Turkish Central Finance and Contracts Unit under the “VOC-Test Center Grant Scheme”. In the course of the “Developing and Operating Machine Tools VOC-Test Center” project, TIAD will establish the occupational standards and vocational qualifications for CNC Machine Tools Mechanical Service Personnel, CNC Machine Tools Electric/Electronic Service Personnel and CNC Machine Tools Application Personnel, in line with European Qualifications Framework (EQF).\n\nAfter the completion of this 24 month project, of which Stichting Kenteq KBB from the Netherlands is a partner, T.R. Ministry of Science Industry and Technology, INMA from Romania and Bahcesehir University, METGEM are the associate partners; TIAD will form a system, establish and operate an “Occupational Standards Development Vocational Knowledge and Skills Testing and Certification Center (VOC-Test Center)” to test and certify the required and sufficient knowledge, skills, attitude, manner and competence of persons who had vocational and technical education and training in the sector; through establishing an authorised accredited institution. TIAD Machine Tools VOC-Test Center will provide Vocational Qualification Authority (VQA) approved certificates that shall be required in the process of employment of the sector professionals and have acceptance both at national and international levels."
        title="TIAD VOC-Test Center Project"/>

    <paragraph
        content="TIAD informs its members and machine tools users of the most up to date technical and technological developments in local and global markets through its bi-monthly published TT Magazin.\n\nSince 2004, TT Magazin with its high quality and informative content has kept its readability rate at high levels and brings together the advertising companies with their target groups by accurate and effective distribution. It is now one of the leading sectorial magazines published with 4,000 hard copies for every issue and 5,000 hard copies for fair specific   special issues and it is sent to 7,000 e-mail addresses throughout Turkey. In total this makes 11,000 people following regular issues and 12.000 people following fair specific special issues respectively.\n\nTT Magazin is sent to these sectors:   White Goods Industry, Piping Industry, Iron and Steel Industry, Ship and Rail Wagon Industry, Construction Equipment and Machinery Industry, Metal Ware Industry, Metal Processing Equipment and Machinery Industry, Automotive Industry, Agriculture Tools and Equipment Industry.TT Magazin is also distributed to the Chambers of Commerce and Industry, Libraries, Commercial Attaches and to companies and associations in similar fields, in addition to being handed out to related fair organizations free of charge."
        title="TT Magazin – Machine Tools and Manufacturing Technologies Magazine"/>

</home>