<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<home>

    <paragraph
        content="Association of Turkish Machine Manufactures was established in 1990, as non governmental organization and is the major national organization in the field of machinery in Turkey. As end of August 2005, MIB has 183 member companies.\n\nIt is representing not only machine tool manufacturers, but also the companies manufacturing wide range of general machineries, machine parts, accessories and cutting tools. In its portfolio, manufacturers of construction, earth moving, mining and agricultural machineries, machine tools; both metal cutting and forming, wood working, packing machines and machineries for process industries, food processing and packing machines, ovens, balancing machines...are present.\n\nThe machinery manufacturing industry has particular importance for Turkey, due to its promising export potential. In 2004 Turkey exported 4.1 billion US $ equilavent of machinery to different countries. 60 % of them exported to European countries, USA and Canada. Expected export at the end of 2005 is 5 billion US$. According Gardner Publications Inc, Turkey is 14th in the world and 7th biggest in Europe, according to CECIMO statistics as machine tool manufacturer.\n\nMIB plays significant role in the development and growth of machinery sector. It encourages the manufacturers participating in various international fairs and exhibitions staged abroad and in Turkey, to integrate them to global world market. It also urges manufacturers for conforming EU’s essential health and safety requirements for machinery, related with the harmonization works in line between Turkey and EU.\n\nMİB has very close relation with the similar associations and institutions throughout the world, as well as in Turkey and also maintains permanent connections with the state bureaucracy.\n\nMİB is member of CECIMO (European Committee for Cooperation of Machine Tool Industries) since November 1999. MIB is also member of PNEUROP (European Committe eof Manufacturers of Compressors, Vacuum Pumps, Pneumatic Tools and Allied Equipment), since May 2005.\n\nMIB actively participates, promotes and supports member’s activities in production and export, also tries to enhance the common benefits of all sector companies. It protects members’ rights and as a result of this, generates solutions for the problems encountered by members; e.g. in taxes, custom regulations, investment incentives and European regulations."
        title="ABOUT ASSOCIATION of TURKISH MACHINE MANUFACTURERS"/>

</home>